#### AHILLA HAFFAT KAMMALA

Jombang, Indonesia | +6282233229091 | <u>kammala88@gmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/ Ahillakammala | https://journeykammala.000webhostapp.com/

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a passionate and meticulous computer science student with a strong dedication to software development. I possess solid skills in various programming languages such as Java, Python, and JavaScript, along with experience in developing web and mobile applications using modern frameworks like Vue.js, React, Next.js, and Flutter. In every project, I ensure quality and efficiency through a methodical approach, adhering to industry best practices, including the use of microservices architecture and CI/CD pipelines. In addition to my technical abilities, I have sharp analytical skills and a strong understanding of system design, focusing on scalability and performance. My experience working on software development projects as both a front-end and full-stack developer is further enhanced by utilizing the Agile SDLC methodology, ensuring iterative, collaborative, and adaptable development processes.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Indonesia

January 2024 – June 2024

Full Stack Developer

- Reengineering Dashboard KPPN KI On Microservices Digit.
- Continued Development of UMKM Financing Empowerment (U-FinE) On Microservices Digit.

#### Dicoding Indonesia - PT. Presentologics

August 2023 – December 2023

Full Stack Developer

- Learn the structure and implementation of JavaScript programming.
- Cloud Practitioner Essentials (AWS Cloud).
- Build a web service using Node.JS.
- CI/CD pipeline implementation.
- Build a Microservices architecture.

Coding Studio December 2023

**Fundamental Penetration Test** 

- XSS.
- SQLI.
- Bruteforce.
- CSRF.
- Command Injection.
- File Inclusion.
- File Upload Vulnerability.
- SSRF & SSTI.
- Reporting.
- Web penetration test on DVWA.

### Koperasi Urun Dana Sejahtera

April 2023 - July 2023

Front End Developer

- Create UI and Admin Dashboard using Bootstrap SCSS and Vue.js.
- Fetching API from Laravel 9.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of National Development "Veteran" East Java

July 2021 - Present

Bachelor of Informatics, Faculty of Computer Science | GPA: 3.79 / 4.00

### **SMA Negeri 3 Jombang**

July 2018 - June 2021

Mathematics and Natural Sciences

#### **PROJECTS**

# Full Stack Web Developer - (BNSP)

# (Ketahesan Swasembada - Web App)

October 2024

Creating Ecommerce Web Application For Medical Tools

- Create databases for Users using Mongodb.
  - Build a Rest API using Node.js Express.
  - Creating UI Web Application Using Next.Js 13 app router.
  - Integrating SMTP using Nodemailer.

### Full Stack Mobile Developer - On Progress

### (TrashBack Mobile App)

June 2024

Creating Mobile Applications for the Waste Management Movement Plastic in Mountain Area.

- Develop system design.
- Create UI TrashBack Mobile App using Flutter.
- Fetching Api from Flask for Machine Learning Features. (On Progress)
- Create databases for Users Application using Firebase and Zoho SMTP.

### **Frontend Developer**

#### (U-FinE - Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Indonesia)

June 2024

Developing Features U-FinE Web Application

• Developing features available in the debtor menu on the U-Fine web application.

### **Frontend Developer**

#### (Dashboard KPPN KI - Ministry of Finance of the Republic of Indonesia)

February 2024 - May 2024

Reengineering the KPPN KI Dashboard

- Reenginering design dashboard KPPN KI using Vue.js.
- Fetching data from the KPPN KI database through the dashboard using Vue.js developed by a Backend Developer with Node.js.

### **Frontend Developer**

#### (Client: Koperasi Urun Dana Sejahtera – Surabaya)

April 2023 - July 2023

Creating Web-Based Applications at the Crowdfunding Sejahtera Cooperative

- Design dashboard views for users using Bootstrap.
- Design login and signup views using Bootstrap.
- Design the admin view using Bootstrap.
- Integrate Rest API using Laravel 9.

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Sept 2023 - Dec 2023

#### (Capstone Project Studi Independen - Dicoding Academy)

Creating Web-Based Applications for the Waste Management Movement Plastic in National and Mountain Park Areas

- Develop system design using UML (Unified Modeling Language).
- Create databases for Users and Admins using Mongodb.

- Build a Rest API using Next.js 13 App Router.
- Assists in creating a visual design of the website interface using Figma, ensuring a modern and intuitive user experience.
- Helps the frontend to create a modern and interactive User Interface.

# **SIDE PROJECTS**

• Camera Operator and Documentary Director - Mengukuhkan Identitas

On Progress

(Subject: Ludruk Budhi Wijaya, Abah Kartolo, Mas Tri (Ludruk Artist), Mbah Imam (literature lecturer STKIP PGRI Jombang), Budi (**Anak Sampir**))

This documentary film was made to revive and reaffirm the identity of ludruk, which is currently unfamiliar in its own birthplace, Jombang.

• Documentary Director - Nguripi

May 2022

(Subject: Forest Protection and Spring Conservation Group, Mendiro, Wonosalam)

This documentary film was made to invite people to care more about nature and ecological balance starting from a small scope, namely the environment around us first.

• Camera Operator and Director Short Movie Documentary – 9.9

November 2022

(Subject: Kenjeran Beach Coastal Community)

The film titled "9.9" is a documentary film that tells about the environmental conditions in the Kenjeran Beach fishing village area in the face of increasingly massive garbage and industrial onslaught.

#### ADDITIONAL

#### Softskill:

Video Editor
 Suara Pendidikan Magazine, Madjoe Mapan Films Production House

• Videografer | Madjoe Mapan Films Production House

• **Graphic Designer** | Freelance

#### **Tools and Skills:**

Application Tools
 Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, React, Next.Js, Astro.js, Tailwind, Bootstrap,

React Native, Flutter, Dart, Firebase, Zoho for SMTP.

Database Skills : MySQL, Mongodb, XAMPP, PostgreSQL.
 Machine Learning Skils : Python, Google Colab (Deep Learning, CNN).

DevOps skills : Jenkins, Docker Desktop, Prometheus, Grafana, Git, Github.

Operating System : MacOs, Ubuntu, Kali Linux.

Design Tools : Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD.

• Collaboration Tools : Zoom, Github, Google Space.

Languages : Indonesian (Native), English (Passive)